Binding... of Isaac.
Shall be played today.
Listen to this.
I come prepared today.
This is the first can I've opened in over a month.
I'm doing it just for today.
Today's a special day.
It's my cheat day.
I ate a bit of candy before this as well.
I admit it.
Cheat day.
It's happening.
Wow.
Fuck.
What messed up chemicals are they putting in this crap?
It's making me feel good.
So good.
Stop being healthy.
I'm not healthy right now.
That's the point.
Wow.
Electrolytes.
It's what humans crave.
Guys, it's time for some more Isaac.
I have to admit last time got me hard.
I mean, it got me excited even more.
Okay.
I crave more Isaac.
I gotta get in there.
Wait, that sounded wrong.
I gotta get back into the free.
You know?
Come on, guys.
I'm just messing with you.
I'm excited.
So, what do you guys think?
Should we do polls today?
I think it's a poll day, isn't it?
I think it makes sense.
So, what should we have on the poll?
Give me suggestions.
I'm gonna make it now.
Wait, how do I do that?
Oh, manage poll.
The poll.
What do we do?
Let me see here.
Challenge is one of them.
Okay, I like it.
What are people saying?
Speed, of course.
Speedrun is a parenthesis, a sasle, or just speedrun?
What do you say?
Which one?
Do people want a sasle?
You know, we can do speedrun and speedrun.
We can do both.
I mean, why not both?
You guys can choose, right?
So, it's all cool.
We're, of course, gonna have a random character.
We're gonna have greed.
Oh, yeah, right.
I'm gonna split the vote with that, you're right.
Let's do just speed then, speedrun.
And then I can choose whether or not to do a sasle, I guess.
Challenge is already on the list.
Isaac d6 can be one of them, I guess, but that's very specific.
What else is there to do?
So, we have speedrun, random, challenge, and greed so far.
These are the four.
We don't need more, right?
That's it.
Okay, let's do it.
We're gonna say one minute on that.
There you go.
Let's see what we get.
And remember, we're gonna rerun this poll every time I fail a run, or win.
Dude, speedrun is popular.
Wow, nobody wants greed?
Where the greed people at?
I think greed and joy, yeah.
No, there's four of them.
Four greed and joy, there's five.
I think greed is fun.
Random not so popular, actually.
Here's what we're gonna do.
If speed wins, which I think it's gonna do, we're gonna do a random speed.
And then the next time, if speed wins again, we're gonna do Azazel.
Because I probably failed the first time around, so, you know, Azazel's gonna come back and make me happy again.
This is the plan.
Dude, maybe we should start speedrunning games in general, you know?
What if I started speedrunning Minecraft, guys?
You know, go full heart.
We're gonna go look at all the tutorials for speedrunning strats.
And we're going hard.
Okay, maybe not that hard, but it would be fun as like one stream, you know, to do something like that.
Okay, so speed won by an overwhelming amount, followed by challenge.
We're not just gonna do one thing, though.
So if the next, you know, poll is gonna be speed again, I'm gonna disregard it.
It's the second option that wins, you know?
We can't do two of the same things in a row.
That's the rule.
Okay, but speed it is for now.
Let's see here.
I'm gonna turn that down.
We're gonna open up the music of Azazel.
I mean, Isaac.
Of course.
Oh, we should also review the notes before we start.
What did I write?
Next stream, massive speed.
We did that already, so let's remove that.
Check item list next time.
I could do that.
Remember Bethany, she's calling.
If the random vote wins, I guess.
Oh yeah, I did mention the new backlog.
Exclamation mark, backlog if you want to see the link.
These ones, I'm not so sure about.
Play last verse to unlock new character.
Done.
Did that.
Bring him the photo.
Oh, dude, last time we got the choice between Polaroid and negative.
That's actually kind of exciting.
What else did I do?
Fight room.
All right, this one.
I think today I may also start to investigate this a bit more.
I did take a picture of this once, but I don't know, man.
I think we need a bunch of pictures to actually understand a, you know, a pattern, I guess, if there is one.
But that's the plan.
That's the plan.
Let's do this.
We're doing a speed run on random.
Here's the thing, though, guys.
No, no, I was about to make some kind of excuse.
Like, if I get a character that isn't suited for speed run, I'm just not gonna do speed run.
But no, no matter what, we're speed running.
It doesn't matter what we get.
Let's go.
Say so, say so, say so.
It's the whore.
Again.
She can't get enough.
That's fine.
So if we gotta go fast with the whore, we have to be on low HP.
But I'm not gonna intentionally, you know, go low HP right now.
Especially when I don't know how much HP I have.
Come on, kill him.
Also, hold on.
I gotta take off my watch.
It's kind of annoying.
You can't fully game with the watch on.
I need to be free.
This room took forever.
I think I gotta change up my speed running strategies as well, because I'm not that fast, you know?
I need to be faster.
Especially when we have a character that isn't very fast by design, you know?
Like Azazel.
You gotta switch it up a bit.
Which means potentially skipping rooms or, you know, something like that.
Okay, we got a treasure room here, though.
That's good.
Go, go, go.
Yeah, just take it.
We don't have time.
Uh, I don't have any money either.
We go.
Oh, this room is crazy.
Uh, follow, follow into my creep.
Yeah, that's how we do it.
Use the creep, use the creep.
Nice.
This guy's gonna die now.
And there we have the boss.
Go!
Larry!
Ah, that's actually good.
We're gonna make him walk into the creep.
Oh, that was very effective.
Oh, yeah!
We got HP as well?
That's huge.
Go!
What a start!
It doesn't get much better than that, I think.
Uh, you know what?
Let's do this.
Uh, what's that?
Two of diamonds?
Two.
Let's do it.
And now we're gonna transform.
All according to plan.
Uh, you know what?
Uh, no.
We're too slow.
Give me that.
I think, uh, this way.
Get him.
Oh, we're actually kind of close to dying here.
Uh, Magneto?
Yeah, okay.
I gotta play safer.
Oh, man.
Okay, good, good.
I'm scared of the poop.
Good.
We got a tinted rock here.
Uh, no bomb, though.
What is this room?
Line him up!
I'm not gonna pick that heart up.
I'm gonna use this bomb on this in here.
Uh, sure.
I have no keys, so it's actually good.
Oh, no, wait.
This is the one that gives me hearts.
Oh, I thought it was the one that made, uh, me, uh, open red chests or something.
Oh, that's a shop.
Uh, we don't have time for that.
Or money.
Shit.
This ain't good.
I may have to go get that HP.
Even though we're gonna transform.
It is what it is.
Safety before anything else right now.
We're probably gonna get hit anyway, and then we're gonna be transforming, you know?
Oh, so he's gonna walk in my creep.
That's the damage I need.
Yeah, jump on my creep.
That's good!
Good damage.
More health.
Sure.
Go, go, go!
And we're ahead of the timer.
Here's the thing, though.
We gotta also, uh, not just stay ahead of the timer, but also prioritize a little bit.
So what do we have here?
Tannic Bible?
Is that the one with, uh, yes, dude, this one is sick!
Book of Belial?
That's not too sick.
This one is sicker.
Nice.
Now we're rocking.
We gotta find, like, a way to reduce our red hearts.
That's the only thing right now.
Okay, well, that's one way to kill enemies.
Magneto!
Are you gonna poop with me?
What do you got?
Oh yeah, step on my creep.
Man, this creep is actually so useful!
There's one more.
There you are.
Okay.
Oh, sick!
I didn't actually mean to pick that up, but okay.
This is awkward.
Okay.
Still need a key so we can get to that treasure.
Come on, man.
This room is rough.
Okay, there we go.
Thank you.
This is a very early, uh, satanic Bible, by the way.
We're gonna get a lot of use out of that.
Oh my god.
My damage is shit!
I need to transform!
I need to become the whore.
Too bad they're flying.
Can't be affected by my creep.
Dude, I have no damage!
I can't kill him!
Fucking finally.
Oh man, too bad.
Health's a resource.
Makes me clear faster.
The satanic Bible is actually a damage-dealing item.
It's not about healing.
It's about damage.
Where's my key?
I can't believe there's no key!
Okay, no more bomb usage.
You gotta save the rest.
You can spawn as many flies as you want.
I don't care.
Uh, maybe I care a little bit, actually.
Yeah, I actually care quite a bit.
These flies are behind the boss!
I can't see them!
What kind of bullshit is that?
Okay, here's a bomb.
Stay at max range.
Okay, not bad, not bad.
Ouija board, spectral cheers, I like it.
Uh, man, I gotta go!
I wish I had a key so I can fucking get the treasure room, man!
So sad.
Okay, okay, uh, go here.
The fucking flying enemies.
It's gonna take me forever to clear.
That was so nice.
And there's the key I needed.
I should have taken damage before I used that, actually.
That was a mistake.
He actually ran into the fire.
Okay.
No.
Ah, worth.
I saw that coming.
Man, I'm kind of killing this guy.
Hey, hey, not bad.
Okay, use the creep.
Oh, that's nice.
Follow me, follow me.
Lovely.
Good damage.
Oh, yo, look at this!
Jupiter, oh, this again.
Okay, we can do that again.
I mean, that's a good amount of damage there, that's what I need.
I'm gonna stand still for a bit so we can poop.
Yeah.
Lovely damage.
There's my key.
Oh, yo, sick.
There's probably more in these rooms.
13 coins?
Yeah, we can maybe buy something.
Yo, we can definitely buy something.
Mystery gift.
Dude, I'm actually gonna take that.
Yeah, I'm gonna come back for the Bible.
I think the boss is down here.
I'm gonna use this gift in, what do you call it?
If we get a trade room, whatever it's called, you know.
We have 36% chance.
Okay, we're gonna line these guys up, look.
And then I'm gonna wait for them so I can fart on them.
Yeah, nice.
Where the hell is the boss?
I'm gonna fart, fart.
Yeah, the damage is sick.
Okay, no time, we gotta go.
Treasure room?
I could use the gift in there, actually.
Wait, I don't have a key?
Fuck!
I have such a shortage of keys.
Oh my god.
Get farted on.
I feel like I'm not doing enough damage here.
Oh, okay, okay.
Keep farting on them.
Okay, okay.
Not bad.
What do we get?
A sacrificial dagger.
Over all the knife, okay, cool.
Man, we didn't get a...
We didn't even get a trade room.
Okay, oh dude, dude!
We're gonna go to a planetarium.
I'm gonna use it there.
Okay.
And maybe we can get a key as well, and come back to the treasure room.
Okay, so keep going right.
I think we're still ahead of the timer.
I'm kind of tempted to go into that.
Actually, wait a minute.
Yeah!
We're curious.
Speed up plus...
What is that?
Most doors remain open in rooms with enemies.
In fact, does not apply to boss room doors or ones that require...
So what?
We can get into the treasure room!
It's all coming together.
Look at that butt!
You see the butt?
That's amazing.
Haha, baby!
We don't have time.
We're going, we're going, we're going.
We're leaving.
It's fine.
It doesn't matter.
This is two treasure rooms now that I haven't been able to access in this run.
That is just straight up unlucky.
That is not even on me.
That's just being super unlucky.
Like, not finding any keys at all.
That was crazy.
Also, I have no damage.
Dude.
Jesus Christ, what a room.
Honestly, yeah.
Take me down to low HP.
I forgot the Bible!
Oh my god.
I may as well just start over.
This is just a disaster.
I can't believe it.
I'm gonna take a sip.
A sip of shame, man.
Also called SOS because I need help.
I'm in dire straits, man.
And now we got the key.
The key that I've been looking for.
No, let me take damage here.
Guppy's head.
What was that one?
Okay, well, sure.
That sounds cool, I guess.
Just make creep and hope they walk on it.
Don't take that.
Mom is here.
Oh my god.
Wow.
Mom's hand is poisoned.
Good stuff.
He's gonna shoot me, no?
He was about to shoot me.
Treasure room.
Here we go, baby.
Bomb back.
Okay, sure.
I mean, that's gonna be my damage, right?
Come here now.
Whoa!
Wait!
Oh, wait, did I just take damage from the freaking rainbow?
What's that, monkey paw?
Oh wait, is it not re- Okay, it's not updated.
There we go.
Sponsor black card when Isaac was used to half a heart.
Let's drink it.
It's consumed after triggering three times.
Okay, well, that's kind of cool, I guess.
Get rid of this.
Kill this guy, kill this thing.
Wow, nothing happened.
Wait, no, no, wait, oh, oh, we got HP!
We got HP from that!
Okay.
Is that what it does?
Maybe it's like a randomized effect.
Sometimes it heals, other times it does other things.
Just like all the other rainbows, right?
I guess we'll find out.
We don't have time, we gotta go.
Fart!
Just die, please.
Keep spawning flies.
Uh, I can't get in there.
Oh, that's such a tease!
Fine.
The bloat.
Uh, I can also try this dagger, I guess.
Oh my god.
Okay, you do that.
Oi!
Okay, then.
Wow, I think I'm gonna die, guys.
This is crazy.
Are you gonna do laser?
Is that a laser?
No, that's jump, okay.
Ooh, that was close.
That was really close.
I'll be taking that.
Uh, man, where are my devils at?
Jesus.
God, I'm so sad I forgot my Bible.
It's actually a generational blunder right there.
I could have had so many black hearts, dude.
And I still don't have a frickin' key to get in there.
That's crazy.
Oh, that was good.
What's this?
Oh, that's a paw!
Yes!
Very nice.
Kill them all.
Oh, fuck.
Okay, these guys are actually not that bad.
They look scary, but they're just posturing.
Eat the pill.
Yes!
Ah.
Good shit.
Oh, treasure room?
Ah, we don't have a key.
Oh, that was sick.
Puberty.
Puberty again.
We can get our HP down.
Oh, I got hit by the spikes?
Or what?
I thought I was close enough not to get hit by that.
Thanks.
Now we have the damage.
And you know what?
We're not fast enough, actually.
We're really not fast enough here.
Wish me luck.
I'm gonna die here for sure, though.
I don't feel good about this.
This is bad.
Oh, no, I got hit.
Okay.
Okay, okay.
Dude, is it just me or am I killing it or what?
Holy shit, I'm good.
So, wait a minute.
I need to see this.
Taking damage with half or less red hearts will trigger an invisibility.
Bubble allows access to higher stages.
Can be used to open a strange door.
I'm assuming this strange door is in this higher stage.
And look at this one now.
This gives me damage.
Taking damage with half or less will trigger a mass damaging effect.
Allows access to deeper stages.
Can be used to open a strange door.
I'm assuming this is a different strange door in the deeper stage.
Right?
I'm taking that.
We're going down.
We're going in here.
Silver...
No, give me that.
I need that.
See ya.
Thank you.
Bye-bye.
Okay.
Summon these.
I'm in deep shit, though.
HP is not looking great here.
This is definitely not fantastic.
I wish I had the Bible.
Imagine having the Bible.
Just imagine.
Dude, me being lost is not going to help here, either.
Okay.
We're getting some bombs, though.
No, don't take that.
No, thanks.
Oh, I'm stuck here.
Nerd.
Getting lots of bombs.
No fucking way!
Oh, we're so dead, actually.
One hit and we're down.
Down.
Oh, my god!
Kill him!
I'm screwed, guys.
I'm screwed.
There's no way I'm going to survive this.
I don't want to pick that up.
I need the damage, I think.
If anything, I need black hearts.
Oh, shit.
How do I dodge?
Oh, oh.
The eyes are going to be the enemy.
Thanks.
Okay, okay.
Keep going.
I'm in deep shit.
I'm in deep shit!
Oh, my god.
Wow.
Oi, oi, oi, oi, oi.
I feel like it's not about speedrun anymore.
It's just about survival.
You stay.
Holy shit, man.
Kill him fast.
Good.
So much farting.
Uh, no thanks.
Oh!
I'm in trouble.
Oh, my god.
How am I alive?
How?
I wasn't even close to them.
I was lined up, man.
I call bullshit on that.
Is it because I was big and fat and ugly?
I think it's because I was too big and fat.
Yeah.
That's funny.
Okay, so on the poll, the second one that was on the list, other than speedrun.
I forgot, man.
Let me see.
View results.
It was a challenge.
Let's do a quick challenge.
And then we'll take it from there.
Oh, yeah, look at all this.
Man, why is eight not unlocked, huh?
That probably means we're going to be cursed on every floor with something.
Okay.
Wow.
Wait, what?
We're playing as Magdalene.
And oh, I see.
There's a bunch of cursed rooms.
Oh, crap.
Okay.
Interesting.
Let's go in here first.
Infestation.
Spawn a bunch of...
I mean, we're going to have a lot of flies then.
If this works on the curse doors, that's going to be good.
I'm still in speedrun mode.
I don't need to be in speedrun mode.
We're chilling now.
We're chilling.
Oh, the boss is here.
Let me find this first.
Let's see what we find in here.
And oh, wait.
That's like the worst item on this character.
Are you fucking kidding me?
What a cruel joke.
That is horrible, man.
That would mean I have only one red heart at a time.
But nine times, you know.
It's going to be hell walking through curse rooms with that.
Wow, look at this guy.
Why is this one so easy?
Usually, it's not this easy.
Amazing.
We go back, of course.
Whoa, box of friends.
I can duplicate my flies with that.
Let's see if I can get some more coins.
Oh, I need one more coin.
Fuck, this should be doable, right?
Maybe if I blow...
Oh, I don't have a bomb.
No.
Okay, this way.
Okay, we got coins, but can we get to them?
Yes, we can.
Wait a minute.
Do I blow this up, though?
Or do I...
We also have a secret room, right?
So let's save a bomb for that.
Dude, we're going to have so many flies.
Holy fucking shit.
I'm awake.
I kind of want to heal, though.
I duplicated all of my friends.
I'm going to bomb here.
Okay.
Bomb it.
Totally worth.
I think I'm going to blow this guy up, too.
No, I'm going to save my last bomb.
Keep making flies.
I wonder if there's an upper limit.
I can't just make infinite flies, right?
Wait, there's only five stages.
Six stages.
So weird seeing that bees are small.
Also, I can see all the secrets, it seems.
Like, I just have full view of the map.
Uh, a bomb for me.
I get this so I can plan out my routes.
Oh my god, they just die.
Wow!
Bro, had no chance.
Oh yeah?
Flies against flies.
An egg?
Cone head.
Hard headed.
Plus one soul heart, 20% chance to negate damage taken from it.
Survival item.
I like it.
Me likey.
We got eight coins as well, in case we want to buy something.
Now, I have a charge ready on the thing, so I may as well go in here.
Wait.
Why didn't I take damage going back?
Is it the cone head?
No way!
That works against that.
Wow.
Crazy.
Wait, careful.
Oh my god!
What?
That door is opened.
I'm going to open here.
Thank you.
Can we get more of these?
Do I give him bombs?
Maybe a couple.
Don't eat all my bombs now.
One more.
Oh, you bastard.
I feel like I got to give him more.
Nah, it's okay.
I missed the actual curse room.
Hahaha!
I feel like I should plan out my routes better here.
I definitely should have gone up there first, and then gone down.
I learned my lesson.
We got battery.
What's this?
Blank card.
Triggers the effect of the card, help without consuming it.
Imagine if you have the sun, and you have this as well.
That is actually like an insane combo.
Like infinite healing, infinite everything.
It could actually be massive, right?
I don't think I want anything in here, actually.
I'm not going to go back.
I'm going to go to the boss.
Okay, then.
Calm down, calm down!
Dude, Magdalene is...
like a tank, almost.
Caffeine.
Oh, some speed is much needed.
And some size decreases also much needed.
Oh well.
And that's what it is.
The Book of Sin spawns a random pickup.
Ooh, that's nice.
Definitely taking that.
Should I take this?
I think not, because I already have an active that I like quite a bit.
Yep, I'm happy with that.
And let's go.
This challenge is fun, man.
Okay, let's plan this route amazingly now.
So, let's say we start by going left, clear all of that.
Then we go up, clear all that, and then right.
Sounds good to me.
Actually, let's start by going...
Yeah, left is good.
Left is good.
Thank you.
I'm going to blow this up.
Okay!
Not bad.
I think I'm going to open this.
Fight room!
Good.
Come on.
They have homing tears, but I have long tears.
Sweet.
Fragmented card.
New floors will generate an additional secret room.
Wait, so we're going to have like three?
Oh, wait a minute.
Child's heart is actually kind of big for me.
Nah, I want this.
Especially now that I can see every room, it's actually worth more.
If you think about it.
Um, let me see.
Let's go down now.
What a weird room.
What the hell is this?
Well, that was weird.
All right.
I saw a tinted rock.
Maybe on the way back, we can try and grab it.
I don't know if it was actually grabable.
D10, it involves all enemies in the room, it's the lower enemies.
I mean, it's good, but I feel like mine is essential, the one I have now.
Because of the situation we're in here, right?
We don't really have a choice.
I got to stick with this.
North is done.
So how do I do this?
If I...
Okay, check it out.
Oh, I'm an idiot.
It can't go across water.
Uh, hmm.
Yeah, that's a rip.
Too bad.
Oh, no.
Oh, we're fine.
Shop room is coming up and we are rich.
Secret here.
I can't come back for it because of the curse rooms.
It doesn't work.
Ah, well, that was a rip.
Not much I can do there.
Oh, that's huge right now.
Restock.
Oh, that could be good.
Maybe...
Actually, I think I want to buy a heart.
I know it sounds like a boring thing, but I need it, man.
I do.
We can buy two of them now because we got that.
Yep.
Wait, it's six now?
What the fuck?
Fine, be that way.
Dude, this boss is gonna get smacked.
Don't waste all the flies.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
Ultimate smackage.
Slabby slap, bitch.
Ohoy!
That was a good amount of damage, huh?
That was pretty good.
More damage and black hearts.
I love it.
Actually, that's just gonna make me sad.
Don't destroy these.
I can't get what's in it anyway.
Cheers.
Dude, we actually can maybe do a speedrun.
I'm catching up to the timer.
Okay, well, that was not really worth it.
Too bad that when you enter a room and taking damage on entering, that the damage effect doesn't apply to the enemies in the room.
That was a long sentence.
Wasted all my flies.
Feels good.
Okay, uh, this way.
More pills.
Oh!
What's that?
And, uh, what is that?
Can't just spawn a card?
We have a card, a pill, a rune that was used.
Huh.
Uh, I think I like this more.
Wait, give me a pill.
Nice.
Magdalene has suddenly become very small.
I should have bombed my way into that room.
That was a mistake.
Okay.
Let me bomb my way in here.
Nice, more bombs.
That means I can get in here now.
Ah, but I don't have any money, so maybe I don't want to.
They're gonna take my battery.
Oh, did I just, uh...
I just turned them off.
Did you see that?
They saw I had no battery, so they were like, no, no, no, let's just chill out for a bit.
That's actually kind of new.
I didn't know that.
There's the boss.
Tell me what...
Ooh!
Disco!
Whoa, what's that?
Dog?
Uh, breakfast?
Gong food?
All you can eat.
What is that?
Tear, shot, speed, plus one health.
Heels all red hearts.
Causes all future pedestal items to rotate between their original item and run random HP.
Oh!
Ha!
It's a buffet!
Yo, that's sick.
Okay, I like it.
Let me go in here.
Wasted all my flies there.
Honestly, I'm just gonna sit at range.
The flies are never gonna come over here.
Look, they're just chilling.
Did I just discover a way to cheat this boss, or like, uh, cheese him?
Look at this!
He can't do anything.
That's amazing.
I'm actually gonna save that blue heart.
Oh!
Oh, I see.
Wait, uh, I need to pause so I can read.
Red health, chance to spawn a red heart and take him down.
That is...
Dude, old bandage is crazy for me!
And the other one?
Shot, speed, luck, health.
That's also good, but I think the other one is even better.
I'll be taking that.
Amazing.
Heel up, and then we're gonna go back.
That's right, we're not done here.
The question is, though, when I take damage by going through a room, will the heart spawn in the previous room or the new room?
Because this is gonna make a big difference.
Guess we'll find out.
Wait, if it even works on walking through doors.
Maybe it's only by enemies.
I got it, right?
I'm not sure.
Thanks.
I don't think it's ever worth it to destroy that guy, actually.
Oh, really?
It better be good.
Okay, a bunch of bombs is good, I guess, but...
Fine.
Whoa!
Hey, treasure room.
Wait, it's every single pedestal.
For some reason, I read it as boss pedestals, but hold on.
Midnight snag is good.
The other one?
Epiphora.
Shooting continuously in one direction gradually increases fire rate.
I mean, that is good as well.
Do I need damage?
Let me see, 5.886 damage.
Getting luck would be kind of nice, I guess, since I don't have any.
It's also plus one damage there.
Oh, this is also damage, yeah, actually.
I think midnight snack.
Yeah.
We're going to the buffet, people!
All you can eat.
And it feels good.
Feels real good.
Thank you.
Ten coins?
We could go to the shop now.
Yeah, let's go.
I'm gonna take a trip through here.
Open that up.
Wait, they even...
Oh my god, even in here.
Oh, hey, yo, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Dude, this is crazy.
This is like the best run of all time.
Shot speed, luck, health, okay.
And this one was damage.
I think I want damage instead, actually.
Wait, what?
Oh, wait.
Oh, no, I can't even afford it.
I just assumed I could get it.
I don't have the money!
Oh, no.
I got so excited.
Oh, man.
Fuck.
But I can buy this thing, though, for ten.
I don't want it.
Oh, that's such a buskill.
Fine.
I'll be moving on.
Cheers, guys.
I think the speed run is ripped, by the way.
Let me see the time, actually.
17 minutes?
If it is 20 minutes, it could be done.
The boss is all the way up top left, though.
Ah, I'm not going to speedrun.
Fuck it.
We're going to do the challenge.
There's actually no need to, I guess, if you think about it.
In the challenge, there's no need to do it.
I don't know why I'm wanting to do that.
I guess I just really like speedrunning.
It's a lot of fun.
It excites me.
What's happening here?
There's nothing in that chest.
Are you a wizard?
Oh, you know what?
Check this out.
There we go.
Ah, man.
Fine.
Look at all the flies I have.
Is my game going to crash?
Wait.
Oh, is this the wizard thing?
Doubles the bombs?
Yeah, sure.
This way.
I got to be a little careful here.
Okay, we can bomb our way through here.
Let me see.
We got 10 keys.
Yeah, why not?
Oh, oh my god.
Rotten meat.
Actually, I should have probably made a door here to go this way.
Yeah, that's a good idea.
Oh, that was totally worth.
You can also get in there now.
Grab.
Oh, wait.
I didn't need that.
Whoops.
Okay, we got battery.
We can use that on the way back.
Dude, these flies are killing it.
Let's go right first.
This is the smart way.
Wait, what is this thing with my damage going up and down?
Let me just see what that was.
Was it that one?
Jackie!
Don't do that.
Jackie just scratched my back out of nowhere.
Or she scratched the chair, which, you know, it's like a mesh.
So it went through the mesh and onto my back.
Uh,
I don't know what's happening with that thing.
Okay, I'm just gonna keep going.
I don't know what's happening.
Make a hole here.
And we have, dude, being able to see the map all the time is crazy.
Just being able to plan your route, you know.
Also, I don't think that the item that spawns hearts when I take damage works on the, uh, what do you call it?
The curse room doors thingies, unfortunately.
It is what it is.
So the boss in the top left, which means I'm going to go right first.
Oh no, I don't want to waste my flies on these when I can just kill them.
Let's see what it is.
Yes, I hate stuff like the Nancy bombs.
I don't care.
This, a hundred percent.
Thanks.
Okay, I just get a bunch of more damage.
It's like every time I get more HP, I get damage up.
Why is that?
I don't understand that.
Jackie, you cannot jump on the table.
Come on.
She thinks it's feeding time, but it's not for another two hours.
Oh God.
Mayday, Mayday.
We have issues.
We've got issues.
Oh no.
God help me.
You can't be serious.
Okay.
We don't know what that is.
I'm going to take it.
Magician.
Gain range.
Foaming shots.
Okay, well, that's nice.
Oh man, really?
Okay.
Okay, that's something.
I mean, okay, okay then.
That was something, huh?
We may be in trouble.
Depends.
No, we have good damage.
Damage is good.
You're dead, son.
Rotten meat or stem cells?
I think rotten meat.
Give me more damage.
Very nice.
I actually kind of want to go back and open this secret room.
That should be, I guess, here.
I have the option to become rich if I want to.
But I'm not gonna.
Apple of Sodom.
Chance to convert a red heart into blue spiders instead of healing.
Maybe, actually.
No, no, no, I want this instead.
I forgot that it was a trinket.
Keep going.
Okay, it's the last stage now.
That should be okay.
I think we're totally killing it here.
Treasure room in the bottom right?
Oh, but I can't see my HP.
Oh, that's a bit scary.
Right?
That frightens me a little bit.
I think I had like eight or seven or six hearts though, so I should be okay.
Oh my god.
Actual gamer.
Nice.
Thank you.
Heal up.
Depression?
Do I want depression or supper?
Let me see what this actually does.
Follows Isaac and spawns.
Trail of damaging blue creep.
I mean, okay.
But I think healing right now is better.
Yeah, I need supper.
Every time I have the option between the healing item and not, I pick the healing item.
Goes to show how much I value those.
It's insane how good they are.
Wait, did I just miss a whole healing heart?
Also, this guy wants copper.
I was about to say, you want copper?
No fucking way.
Wow.
Thanks.
I gladly take that.
Let's go into the actual curse room.
And take some pills forever.
I mean, I could already see forever, so.
Nice.
Ah, tears down, no thanks.
I'm good.
I'm kind of worried that I can't see my HP here.
I'm not gonna lie, this is not a good feeling.
Less tears, no thanks.
Surely we are not dying, right?
Like, we have plenty of HP.
Did all my flies just ran into and get wasted on these guys?
Oh my god, I took damage from that.
That's crazy.
I need hearts.
We're gonna go in here.
Okay,
a little bit of healing is good.
Here's the active.
Nice.
More hearts, I'm so scared.
We gotta go straight for the boss, man.
I am too scared here.
I really am.
It's not looking good.
Oish.
Nice, a whole heart, that's so big.
Hey, wait, what?
Am I literally full on health?
There's no way.
I can't believe that.
Okay, well, in that case.
Mom, you're dead.
You ain't got a chance.
My damage is good.
This is some solid damage.
I'm getting better at dealing with mom.
Oh, I didn't mean to pick that up, but okay.
Solid challenge, huh?
The credit card has appeared.
Nice.
I don't know what that is, but it sounds good.
Okay, I will now veto the vote.
We're doing a sasyl speedrun.
People want a speedrun, right?
And now it's my choice.
I'm gonna put a sasyl on top of that.
Here we go.
I need a little bit of a sasyl fix, okay?
What a start!
Hey, come here.
Oh, no.
Oh, that sucks.
It is what it is.
I can fly.
It's the best realization.
It's like realizing you have candy in the cupboard, you know?
When you forgot about the fact that you had that.
Oh, wait, we're speedrunning.
We can't go slow.
I was about to destroy all those poops.
Good thing I didn't.
You either go full poop or full speed.
Oh, come on.
There we go.
Shop, we don't care about that.
Oh, shit.
Oh, no, you're not.
I can't believe you did that.
Oh, not the bandages.
It's such an underwhelming item.
I just want to throw it in the pooper, you know?
Uh, haka-las.
It's destruction.
I can't step, unfortunately.
Step my foot.
I can't stop.
Is that...
Oh, that's so good, dude.
That's massive for me.
Huge item.
I'm actually gonna...
I'm even gonna go in here.
Fuck it.
That's right.
We're gonna eat all the pills.
We're gonna get speed down.
We're gonna get him at temp-sis.
Sure.
And spiders.
We love it.
That was probably unnecessary.
We're speedrunning, so we can't do that stuff.
I need to pull myself together.
We're gonna do the 15 bosses thing.
I can't wait.
It's so much fun.
Down, down, down.
Come on, come on, come on, go, go.
Wealth of wealth?
Okay.
I can't believe that.
Lock.
Chance to add pickup.
I...
What is the other one?
Chance to gain one additional cent each time you pick up a coin.
Nah, I like this one.
Here we go.
Stephen.
Stephen Bonnell.
Little Stephen.
I can't take any of that.
Go.
Speed.
Pills.
Heave the pills, baby.
Yeah, bubba!
Fuck.
I hate when I'm being put in that situation.
Oh my god.
That opened for some reason.
We don't have time.
We do have time.
No, we don't have time.
I was about to say, we can just quickly grab it, but we can't, because we can't go back until we win the thing, you know?
So, de de de da, de de de boop, de de de de de boop.
I'll take the moon, though.
Money.
A lot of money.
Down, right, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
Oh, I almost...
I did, actually.
Not almost.
I did run into that.
So many stupid mistakes are being made in the name of speedrunning.
Spider-Man!
Oh my god.
I can't even destroy the thing!
I need it.
Okay.
We need to find the boss, anyway.
Go back.
Wow.
Nice, do that.
We don't care about this item.
What's that?
Marked.
Directed tears.
Tears automatically fire at a crosshair on the ground and controlled by...
What?
Huh!
Interesting.
I don't know if I like that.
We'll see.
I mean, it's kind of sick at doing the angled shots here.
Oh, it's kind of cool.
I like it.
That's pretty awesome.
I gotta keep going!
Speed!
We are so far ahead of the timer.
Maybe we can slow down a bit.
Oh no, this again.
Okay.
Sure.
Just give me a bunch of money.
I'll take that.
Oh no.
It's gonna get something taken used to here, for sure.
This is weird as hell.
If only I had brimstone, imagine that.
Open the freaking door.
Oh, we're not done.
Magician...
Uh, you know what?
It's fine.
Good.
What do we got?
Okay, more money.
Man, I'm just getting a bunch of shit.
Ah, this is so weird.
I gotta get used to this.
Whoa.
It feels weirdly bad, but good at the same time.
Beelzebub, Spider Baby, Fire Exact, here's...
...a spawn one blue spider, or fly, upon striking an enemy.
Exact, here, is also slow enemy, struck, and spawn a small pool of slowing creep.
Um...
I'll take it.
Good.
Just do it.
I don't care at this point.
This weird hagalas, I'm not a big fan.
The fallen?
Okay, I mean, sure.
Book of Sin?
I like this more, though.
But wait, wait.
May as well use it once, right?
Angel stuff.
Trinity shield, block shots, and the...
Oh, that's good.
That means we can block in all kinds of directions.
Now look, it's actually kind of dope.
Man, really?
Fuck off.
I'm gonna kill you.
Dude!
Stop shooting the bomb!
Ran out of bombs now, great!
Fine.
I didn't want to kill that guy anyway.
That was legitimately annoying.
What's up, what's up, what's up, huh?
Man, I don't think I like this, uh, mark thingy.
I don't, I don't like it.
I would rather not have it.
I didn't mean to do that.
Complete misclick there.
I showed that room, didn't I?
I'm going here.
Yeah.
I mean, wait, what does that do now if I don't have any red hearts?
Huh, is it just free?
I, I can't use it.
I guess you can't use it then.
Useless.
But hey, let's not forget, I got one out of three on Guppy now, right?
In case we find more Guppy items.
That's something to keep in mind.
Oh, look at this battery.
More battery.
I managed to go in every direction, except the boss direction.
Actually, so sad.
Here we go.
It's war.
Actually, I'm going to kill these stupid fires.
Oh man, really?
What is this guy's deal?
Can you stop that?
Sit in that corner.
There we go.
Dude, more bandages?
We're leveling this guy up though, I guess.
All of, we have three of them now.
Familiar that fires charm tiers.
Okay, what's the next stage though?
Bigger Familia that deals increased damage and has a chance to drop hearts.
I need the next stage of this just to see what's going on with that, you know?
We're moving.
I don't know about this run.
Like, I don't know.
It feels both good and bad at the same time.
It's, I can't explain it.
Oh my God.
Oh my God, stop!
Oh, dice!
Three.
Did I ever figure out what that did?
Let me see here.
I, let me just write it.
Three.
Question mark.
Last time I tried this, it didn't really do anything.
I don't know.
No, I don't want that pill.
Wait, did I just?
Did I change something here?
No, I didn't.
I don't know.
Legitimately confused.
Oh.
Like lasers, huh?
Don't like them when I laser you.
Sure.
Uh, sure.
Yep.
Two of clubs.
Give me that.
I'm kind of rich here.
Donate the rest, man.
Even though we're on a speed run, we got to do this quick.
Good.
Move on.
We are pretty far ahead of the timer, so we're chilling, actually.
Oh, what is this?
I don't like that.
I'm going to assume the boss is not that way.
You'll see I'm right.
Whoa, he has to drop a so hard card, we're going to shrink it.
All right, sure.
Useless.
You know what's confusing about this item?
I realize what it is now.
The little X on the ground.
The way I'm thinking about it, and I can't change my ways, is that I'm just switching the direction of the shot.
But that's not what it is.
I'm choosing a location on the floor, and that's the place I'm shooting.
I can't wrap my head around that.
To me, it's way more natural to just think, oh, I'm shooting in this direction now, you know?
So it's fucking me up a little bit.
That's why the X is in the corner sometimes, all the way across the screen.
Because I just can't.
I can't do it, captain.
What's that?
Pinky-eye, chance to fly a portion?
You know what?
Why not?
I like it.
So the boss was actually in this direction.
You've got to be kidding me.
Well, it's not like we're running out of time, you know?
Gimme.
Let's go.
Oh my god, stop!
Go, go, go, go, go, go.
Oh no.
Dude, I just keep getting hit here.
Why is mom so aggressive today?
Okay!
Jesus!
Well, that was a quick end to that one.
Let's do a pull.
What do we do next?
Next up, challenge, read, random.
I'm going to write random, speed run.
And what is the other one?
Wait, so we have random?
Oh, and just random.
Just random.
There we go.
Voting is up!
Let's see what we get.
Why?
I'm really surprised, actually.
Why people are so excited about the speed run.
I guess playing slower is a little less exciting, I imagine.
Like walking around, you know, penny pinching.
Blowing up every rock, looking under every stone.
Probably not the most exciting thing to watch, I guess.
Well, I think we can already say it's a random speed run win.
It is by a large margin.
Okay.
Let's go.
Let's see what we get.
Eulith!
All right, it's been a while.
Duplicate.
Get them all.
I'm going to have to get used to this.
It needs power?
What did that do, I can?
Increase to all stats when an active item is at full charge.
Okay.
That's actually good for me.
Grant's poison tears.
Yo, and there's also a tinted rock in here?
Keep it in mind.
That's going to be a nice damage increase.
Oh, you got poison?
I got poison too!
Uh...
Yeah, that one is healing.
Uh, shit, shit, shit, shit, shit.
We don't have a bomb.
Go.
Give me that.
There's the boss.
What?
Uh, super magnet?
Uh, no.
Or maybe.
Actually, I think it's actually good.
Yeah, I'm actually going to grab it after this.
Don't push him towards me!
My little followers pushed him towards me there.
That kind of fucked me.
Okay.
Yo, pentagram!
I like that.
Uh, we go quickly back though and grab this.
The stat increase is nice, but being able to just take any pickup?
Also good, right?
Okay.
100% demon chance?
We can't take damage.
We took damage.
Uh, right, we don't have any- Oh, yeah, right!
Only red damage, but I can't see my HP, so that's kind of, you know, ugh.
Little scary.
Dude, come on.
Get out of there, guys!
Oh, I hate this.
Scary, scary!
Actually, hold on.
Maybe I don't want devils.
I want angels.
I'm gonna go for angels, guys.
Man, fuck off.
I think I lost all my non-red hearts.
Like, look at this here.
This is why this item is so good.
Spider baby.
Sure.
Okay, that's a dead end.
Oh!
Everything died.
If I get hit again, we're gonna lose the demon.
Not that I need it, but...
Yeah, I'm actually not gonna- If I take the demon on this floor, I'm actually dead.
Like, the run just ends, I mean.
It's gonna be a tough one.
Especially this guy.
I hate this guy so much.
Please don't jump.
Oh, my god.
Okay, okay, not bad, not bad!
Nice, that's much needed.
I could take this now.
Uh, chance of- Yeah.
No, yeah.
It was a bad idea, wasn't it?
Also,
I forgot about- Never mind.
We're playing Judas- Oh, not this, both!
Yeah, we're dead.
It's over.
It's actually over.
You can't not take damage against this.
Somehow, we survived.
Yeah.
Not for long, though.
Please heal me, heal me.
Yeah!
What's this?
Anakin's cookbook?
Okay, sure.
No, no, I don't know.
I need this.
We need to go faster.
Good.
Let's go up left.
That was a bad spot to be in, why did I do that?
Why did I do that?
Nice.
Speed!
Oh man, oh man, oh man, oh man, oh man!
Yeah, how do you even damage that?
Or dodge that?
Jesus Christ!
Money equals power?
Why not?
Yeah, go.
The speedrun dream is alive.
Ooh, richness!
We are rich now.
Need a shop.
Come on, kill him, kill him, kill him.
Good stuff.
The stars, wait.
Yes, well, let's go in here first.
Five?
Restart current, ooh.
Does that reset the timer?
I wonder.
Let's check what the time is.
Six minutes.
Slimshady, you're on.
You know what?
Let me, let me see.
Six minutes, 43.
I'm testing.
It's just for testing.
Six, no, oh, it doesn't!
Okay.
Well, that's good to know, I guess.
Now I know that.
This definitely just ruined my run a little bit.
But it's all in the name of science, right?
Get back up here.
How?
As in, how am I so bad?
I feel like the layout has changed.
This is not the same layout, what the?
Ha!
I wonder if I get to keep items I find on the floor.
Because if I do, then the ideal way to play, if you're not speedrunning, if that is, is to get everything, restart, and get more.
Is it dead end?
You know what?
I don't like this room.
See ya.
Sad bombs, for sure.
Show me the boss.
We may just die here.
I think I'm dead.
Yeah, I'm dead.
It's hard going fast and being precise.
We're going to do another speed random.
My prayers have been answered.
Oh yeah, this time I'm not going to fuck it up.
We have to treasure the times that we have Azazel.
So you cannot be squandering it.
We're going to be going fast, but not as fast as last time.
We're going to slow things down a little bit, okay?
I feel like the balance is almost there.
I was just a little too fast last time.
A little gish, sure.
Why not?
Because you're already fast as Azazel, right?
You can afford to be a little more careful.
I got no money anyway.
No tidbit rocks.
Here we go.
Clean so far.
Gimme me.
Good night.
Range is massive on Azazel.
No mistakes, precision gameplay.
I'm not going to go in there.
Hey, nice!
I gladly exchanged luck for range.
Hey!
Okay, we're charging up a little slower now.
That's actually kind of bad, but it's not disastrous.
It's okay.
Since we're hitting run strategy anyway, you know, it's good.
Yeah, the charge is definitely slow now.
Pause, okay.
That's straight up for the next floor.
I'm not going to take that.
We got to kill the boss.
We're in good time.
We're not in that much of a hurry.
There's the boss.
What's that?
Oh, cool.
Gurgling?
Wait.
Wow, the damage is really good here.
More range?
Dude, I'm a ranged beast.
Kidding me?
Ceremony ropes.
More damage.
That's really good.
Dry baby.
Dude, this one is a no-brainer, no?
Dry baby blocks and chance to deal instant reward.
That's also very good.
Appreciate the likelihood of a room clear reward.
I'm going to take this.
I feel it.
Three black hearts is a little risky, but bear with me now.
Bear with me.
It's going to be good.
You'll see.
No keys.
Good shit.
Something just opened.
This one.
We don't have time.
Pills?
Sure.
Maybe I prefer the pills, actually.
We don't have a lot of money.
This pill is unknown, but this is a full pill.
Something's wrong.
God, okay.
Keep moving.
We really need some more tears.
Oh my god, no way.
Not that way, down.
We also have a key, so we can't go to the library.
Wait, they have spectral shots?
His shot just went through those rocks.
Boss is here.
We haven't...
We go back for the library real quick.
Nice!
Thank you.
Library, library, library.
There's three books in here.
Book of Sin, Random Pickup.
Useless.
Book of Shadows.
That's the invincibility thing.
And this is the monster manual.
Just do that one.
I think I'll keep this, honestly.
Then again, this is also good.
No, I'm gonna take the pills.
I'm too much of an addict.
I can't stop.
I can't stop taking them.
They're too good.
Move on.
I think we're still in great time here.
Wow!
More damage, range, can be...
Wait, wait!
This is the bad one, right?
For this guy?
Let's see.
No, actually...
It's...
It's okay.
I thought it was the other one that was super bad, but this one is okay.
Okay, go here.
Whoa, you bastard!
Lord!
In my yard.
This is awkward, the way my shots are being warped.
You know what?
I like it.
Do you mind hitting where we're shooting?
What?
Pretty fly.
First thing's sac.
Sure.
Why not?
Insane that I did that.
Wait, do I have infinite range for this?
Yo!
I think I'm using this wrong.
I sit in a corner and I just go, ham!
Look at that!
Oh my god, it's actually good.
It's massive.
Oh yeah!
You ain't shit!
Oh no, more range?
Dude, I'm getting all the range that I don't need right now.
Sure, move on.
Man, this is great.
I'm having a blast with this.
Door open.
We don't have time.
We do kind of have time, actually.
But I'm not gonna.
Play it safe.
No, don't waste the key on that.
Bad idea.
Wow.
Cool.
Look at that, I'm just sitting and cheating.
It feels good.
Uh, weird room.
I have a penchant for picking the wrong direction every single time.
Actually, that's not true.
Let's appreciate the times I did get it pretty quick.
Like, one of these earlier rooms.
Shit.
Even slower tiers.
That's really bad.
We are pretty slow now.
Uh, I can't give that guy anything.
I could blow him up, though.
I don't know how much HP we have, but it's not a lot.
How are you not dead?
Please wake up!
Thank you.
Give me a good item.
What the hell is that?
Replaces tiers with large arcing bloodshots that burst into a spray of smaller bloodshots on impact.
The large shots deal increased damage, but have reduced fire rate.
Uh, what?
I can't even see where I'm shooting!
Wait, I can.
Kinda.
It's...
No, I...
The run is over!
That's it.
We're done.
It was nice knowing ya.
How fun.
Great.
Well, that was that.
Oh my god, dude.
I can't even see where I'm shooting.
I can kinda see it, but not really.
It's like, super bad.
If there's gonna be a room with anything busy that's gonna happen, I'm not gonna see where my shots land.
Even in an empty room, I can't see it.
I'm fucked.
I want that.
I want it so bad.
You know what?
Donate the rest, cause we're about to end the run.
May as well get it all in there.
Donate it all, man.
I don't understand how...
This is...
So weird.
Thank you.
Let's see what we...
Can we overwrite this with something, maybe?
Guarantees all Devil Deals appear.
Or we can dig down.
Uhhh...
No.
I need my HP right now, I think.
I'm good, son.
Move on.
Oh, we had more HP than I thought.
I thought we were like, two Red Hearts.
Shit.
This is the most awkward run now.
It went from so good to mega weird.
It's almost like I have to wait until the shots are up in the air and then I have to aim.
Like, every time.
It's super weird.
Like, I have to visually sort of...
I legitimately can't see!
Am I hitting?
I'm hitting.
That is so weird.
Bad trip?
No, thanks!
I'll take the key, though, because I don't have any.
Mom?
I mean, I will say, though, when the tears land, they do deal a lot of damage.
I'll say that.
Bro, I...
Sure.
I can't!
There's too much black on the floor here!
God, this is disgusting.
Oh, it's my friend.
Ha!
I thought he was an enemy.
Wait, there is someone in here!
Huh?
No idea.
I have no idea what's happening.
Thank you.
D4, re-rolls each item currently held?
Honestly?
Yes!
Get me the fuck out of this situation!
Uh, Jacob's ladder?
Yeah!
Let's try that, dude!
We're gonna ascend up the ladder with Jacob again!
Placenta.
Ouija board.
Guppy's collar.
Pentagram.
We keep that, okay.
Magic scab.
Mitre.
Mom's lipstick.
Nancy Bomb's giant cell.
Okay.
And paperclip.
Ah, we're back with a good attack!
Love it!
Much better.
Run as saved.
Run as saved!
Everything's cool.
I'm curious to see if this electricity is gonna arc via this.
Oh god.
I think it is!
I think it is.
Wait, we actually don't have time for this.
We gotta go, we gotta go.
The only thing is, we still have terrible tears.
So we gotta go...
Oh, we gotta find more tears.
What's this?
The fool.
Tears down.
No, thanks.
Is the boss really over here?
He is.
I can't just shoot the rocks anymore, it seems, though.
I definitely have lower damage now, but it's much more consistent.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, no problem.
And you're dead.
Uh, let me take this one again.
I'm gonna go in here.
Let's fucking go!
What's this?
Capricorn.
Plus one health.
Heels one red heart.
Plus one bomb.
Key coin.
A bunch of...
Oh, uh...
Only a little bit of tears, though.
Let me see what else is in here.
What the hell is that?
Loki's horns.
He has to fire tears in all four...
That, honestly, with Jacob's ladder could be pretty good.
Pupila duplex.
Spectral tears increases their size, giving them a white shape.
That's not gonna matter too much for me, I think.
Holy mantle.
Prevents the first hit.
Ay!
That's the one.
That is the one.
That one is incredible.
Let's get it on.
Where you going?
Dude, I love this, uh...
Well, boss rush, I get it.
Boss rush.
Why is that so hard to say?
Boss rush face.
It's super fun, man.
It's also good practice against these types of enemies, you know?
Like, if you wanna get some...
Get some nice practicing against X or Y, you know?
Kinda cool.
I like it.
Oh, shit.
Give me a pill.
Infested, okay.
Ooh, a heart!
Oh, that's from Mitre, right?
That is actually massive.
I'm gonna kill these small guys.
What was that one?
The fool.
I wonder what happens if I use the fool here.
I'm not gonna do it, of course.
But is it just gonna reset, or what?
Undo my progress?
No!
I really tried to dodge that.
Okay, you're dead.
Oh, I love the sound of the electricity.
Oh, we got pills again.
Friends till the end.
I wish I had a couple more tears, though.
It's just very slow to charge up.
Thanks.
Wait, does Mitre...
Hold on, I need to see.
Uh, convert...
Oh, it's converting red hearts!
I see, okay.
I thought it was when I took damage.
I see how it is.
Ah, man.
Angel down.
Look at this clown.
I got little buddies following me around now.
And the electricity arc is so good against these small guys that keep spawning everywhere.
Just takes them out automatically.
I don't have to worry about it.
More pills.
Tears down, you know, thanks.
Actually, I kind of want to pick this up in case I accidentally use tears down.
Whoa.
Not today.
Thank you.
Yeah, we got this one in the back.
There's no way we lose this one.
You see how I just killed the ads when I attacked the boss?
It's so nice.
Oh, you...
Fuck, you're so fast.
Oh, no.
Whoa, these guys have no chill.
See you, spiders.
I think the little guys are also doing quite a bit of good work here.
Pills infested.
Soon I'm gonna know what all the pills do.
I've eaten so many pills already.
I'm the pill master.
What's that one?
What's that?
I think that's ranged down or something.
Or tears down.
I'm kind of losing a lot of HP here.
It's not good.
I'm gonna play a little bit more safe.
Oh, I can kill this guy.
Good.
There we go.
15 out of 15.
Wish me luck.
Oh, shit.
I probably should kill this guy over here because he's gonna laser me.
And I'm gonna be very unhappy about that.
There we go.
What's that?
Bloodshot eye.
Orbital familiar that blocks enemy shots, deals contact damage, and fire shots and enemies.
Very run-on-the-mill familiar.
Friends till the end.
Okay.
Cheers.
Oh, no, no.
I don't want that.
Kind of curious, though.
If I go out here now and use this, and I go back.
What then?
Oh, wait, shit.
I'm all the way back here.
Can I get another shot at this?
There's no way, right?
Free items?
Up, right, up.
Wait, we don't want any of that.
No, okay.
But I think there's some kind of secret where if you go back with some kind of card...
Because you can't go back normally, right?
It's the ripe location for a secret.
You know?
I don't know what it would be, but it would make sense to hide something.
Okay, let's not take damage from this guy.
Oh, that's huge.
Thank you.
Wait, there's more?
I am so happy that we turned this around.
I was so sad when we suddenly had, I don't know, the worst shot of all time.
And then it became amazing.
Again.
My best buddy.
You know what?
I got coins, but I don't have time.
So sorry.
Man, come on.
Where are you guys?
Bad gas?
What does that do again?
Fart dealing five damage and poison.
Recharge.
Oh, it recharges me?
No, it doesn't.
Nice.
Yo, that's a fast boss.
Rolex.
I just lost my mantle.
Tears down.
Why do I keep finding this shitty pill?
No matter where I go.
Good night.
Bar of soap is extremely underwhelming.
We're gonna keep going.
Arcade.
You know what?
That was a bad idea.
Maybe a good idea.
See, I don't know why I did that, actually.
I have no explanation for my actions.
I'm actually puzzled by my own actions here.
In hindsight, that made no sense.
In fact, it made no sense at all.
I'm gonna go in there and bomb it.
Just because I'm angry now.
I'm gonna bomb him as well.
There we go.
I feel better now.
Electricity!
Yeah!
Good night.
Uh, nope.
We gotta go.
We got- also, what's the time?
25 minutes.
Oh.
Wait, do we even need to speedrun anymore?
I don't think we do.
Unless, uh, the next boss is actually also locked behind speed.
Which could be the case.
Wait, did I just- No, give me the other one.
Are you a wizard?
I forget what that does.
Gimme.
Oh my god, so many blue hearts.
Hey!
Electricity, man.
Gotta love it.
I think Jacob's Ladder might be one of my favorite items.
Not only is it super powerful, it's also just incredibly satisfying to use, you know?
It feels so good.
Like, I'm not even shooting the enemies and I'm hitting them.
That's the power of this.
It lives... not for long!
Oh, shit.
We lost our mantle.
Mama's Boya Chief!
What the fuck?
You rock!
Pop has appeared.
Yo!
Uh, wait.
Here first, here first.
Uh, yep.
Sure, why not?
Just take that.
Go-ho-ho-ho-ho!
Yeah, we're going down there.
I think this one is also gated behind a timer.
You know, when it's like this big hole in the wall, it's the timer.
We're gonna kick some ass now.
What's this?
Empress...
Ah, sure.
Oh, this music, though.
Goes pretty hard.
Let me see.
Uh, two tiers at once, but it's split.
Nah, man.
Leaves a trail of creep that deals...
Wait, copies and tier effects?
That means electricity creep!
Whoa!
That could be pretty sick.
If I'm not misunderstanding that.
I don't know what that is.
Robo-baby?
Fires lasers?
Let me try this.
The intruder.
Invasive friend.
That doesn't sound nice.
Spider familiar that inhabits Isaac's face.
And fires quad shots of slowing tiers in addition to Isaac's normal tiers.
Chancellor taking damage to spawn blue spiders and dislodges the...
Oh, wait, we've had this before!
We must have, uh, had this in challenge or something, since we didn't have it recognized.
Yeah, okay.
Let's go to the shop.
I don't think there's anything good here.
Maybe that one?
Bad trip, nah.
Uh, what is this active here again?
Sharp key?
Nah.
Range!
Hey, hey!
Not bad.
Okay, we're gonna donate the rest.
And it broke.
All right, I think we're good to go, man!
Wish me luck!
It's hush!
Lost my mantle.
I honestly think I'm gonna have trouble against this guy with this build.
Something about it doesn't feel right with me, you know?
I feel like we're gonna die.
What, I could be wrong here.
Response for you.
Whoa!
What the fuck was that?
I need this guy to walk on my creep.
But he's just a big fat blob.
So I guess he's not gonna do that.
I'm gonna put a bomb there.
Oh yeah, we got random bombs.
Electricity goes hard here.
Look at the way it spreads!
Oh god, wow.
Gotta focus.
Oh no, no, no, no, no!
Focus up!
Oh, this is always so messed up here.
Oh man, oh man!
Whoa!
Oh shit, he angry now, he angry now.
But my electricity is strong!
Man, that scream is actually terrifying.
How does anyone dodge this?
Fuck me, dude.
Oh man, my tears are so tiny.
Get out of the way.
Oh, here we go again, here we go again.
Holy shit!
I can dance all day, I can dance all day!
Try and hit me, try and hit me!
Fuck!
Oh my god.
Oh, he angry now.
He mad as fuck!
Please die, just die please.
I need you to die!
Die, die, die, die, die!
Oh, did it say secret exit?
What?
Secret exit?
Wait, we also have healing back here, I gotta go grab that.
Dude, I have no more energy inside of me.
Holy shit.
Dude, if I go in here, I'm gonna...
We're going in.
We're going, baby!
I'm not, I'm gonna die.
Guys, this place is crooked.
I am so fucked in here.
I'm telling you, this is not gonna go well.
The boss in here is insane.
Oh, nice, thanks.
Unlock the little shortcut there.
Gain some money, cool.
I'm gonna bomb him.
Is that an enemy?
That's a friend.
Oh, that's good for me.
We're gonna be operating that mechanism.
I can't wait to operate.
Why are you blue?
Wait, tick.
That's the one I can't get off, right?
When entering the boss room restores one red heart and removes 15% of health from the...
Ooh, yo!
Cannot be rem...
That's honestly not bad.
Am I crazy?
Against bosses?
The fool?
Uh, blast...
Yeah, well, I can't take it anyway.
Blood donation.
Uh, brain worm?
Oh, it's this one.
Missed shots turned 90 degrees.
Ooh, I mean...
Oh, I can't take it, right.
Fucking tick.
I'm not gonna give up.
I'm gonna make you make me give up.
This is just a trinket generator.
The magician is actually pretty good.
Does that work with my laser, though?
Homing shots?
With laser?
We're gonna try it when we find the boss.
Pretty fly.
Or a white guy.
Last eye.
I'm feeling high.
Thank you.
Oh, there's more.
We could potentially go back and maybe gamble with that machine even more.
I will say, though, I feel like my damage is a little underwhelming.
Extra range is...
Oh, wait, I didn't explore up here.
So, there's multiple boss rooms, but it doesn't really matter.
You just gotta pick one of them, I guess.
So, it's all about getting ready and then just entering one of them.
Experimental pill?
Shots speed up HP.
Ooh, I don't know if I like that, actually.
I hate that.
That was not good.
Then again, at this point, does it really matter with the red hearts?
Maybe not that much, you know?
It's all about the blue hearts right now.
Hey, sick.
I can maybe open a door here?
No, okay.
Where should I go?
Probably down.
Oh, give me this.
Go this way.
Yeah.
This one can remove the tick.
That's kind of fun.
I'm not gonna remove it, though.
Good to know I have the option.
More damage.
Why not?
Oh, what's that?
Her throw.
Yo!
Rerolling.
We find something we don't like?
Something's wrong?
No, no, no.
I don't like that.
I want something to be right.
Oh, this room looks crazy.
Wow!
Somehow I did that without taking any damage.
That's crazy.
What's up, dudes?
Black heart?
Don't mind if I do.
Bang a shurn.
Ah, stupid inanimate object.
I don't want bad trip.
I want the good kind.
Uh-oh.
Electricity, baby!
Yeah!
It's so good against this.
No problem.
What is this place even?
It's crazy looking.
Okay, well, I think it's time we actually...
You know what?
Just go for it.
Fuck it.
Let's do it.
Wait, triakonous!
What?
What the hell is that?
Oh, that's new.
Reveal special rooms on the map.
Hey!
Where are they?
I guess I found them all already.
What the hell?
Okay, so it's just different bosses or what?
Okay, that one was, like, really easy, though.
The bloat?
Okay, this is very different this time.
Like, these guys are nothing.
What the heck?
Uh, chaos, bond one six, pickups, all item pedestals draw.
I like that.
I could re-roll it, but I'm not gonna.
What's that?
Oh, yeah, perth row.
Three random cards.
The lovers, starting room, doubles Isaac's keys, why not?
Give me that.
What's this, safety cap?
Increased chance of finding a pill.
This one is locked down.
I don't like that.
Give me that one.
Okay, well, this is cool.
I like it.
Just go one by one now.
Loki.
Is Loki gonna die real fast because he ate shit?
What's up with these pauses?
I can't put tears to apply.
I mean, that's good.
I like this.
I don't even want to re-roll that.
That's great.
Health up.
You know, I take that.
I take those.
There's actually more rooms I didn't explore.
Okay, let's go this way.
Hey, we can do this again.
Hey, just one more.
What's that?
Uh, I can't see what a teardrop charm.
It gives the chance of lock base shots to be fired.
That could be good, actually.
I have some lock base things, I think.
Let me see here.
Nah, nah, nah, I like the current one.
50% health taken off the boss?
Like, that's crazy.
Maybe that's why they die so fast.
Thank you.
I'm just gonna move on.
Oh wait, there's a room down here that I missed.
Okay.
How is this game still so freaking good?
Like, I have so many hours in this game now, and it's still, like, so good to play, you know?
It's insanity.
Ah, I lost my thingy!
Rip.
Oh wait, it's every room!
I thought it was the whole floor!
Dude, the mantle is insane.
Every room?
Okay, dude.
The mantle is actually next level.
Placebo.
Whoa!
Oh wait, it's not a pill.
Uh, let me think.
We gotta maybe come back here in case we get a good pill from Mom's Bottle of Pills.
Wait, it smells like food from the kitchen.
I wonder if Jackie's cooking.
What is she making out there?
Friends till the end.
I don't want to duplicate that.
I think we're maxed on that anyway.
There's a boss over here.
In fact, there's a couple bosses.
Less tears.
Whoa!
Yeah, let's go!
Delirium.
Oh, this is the crazy one!
Uh-oh.
This one is no joke.
We gotta focus.
Wow.
Dude, calm down, calm down!
Okay, okay.
Dude, it's no chill.
Going pretty good so far.
I don't know, why are you?
Oh, there you are.
Oh, kill the little spiders.
This guy's puking a lot.
Oh my god.
Am I even hitting anything?
We are hitting something.
Jesus Christ!
Whoa!
I thought you motherfucker.
What's happening?
What the fuck is going on?
You're done, son!
You're done!
I'm not gonna open it yet.
Hold on, there's still more on this floor.
I'll be back.
We keep going!
We don't stop!
We never st- Oh!
This guy had no chill.
Bring it on, bitch!
Isaac!
I'm an expert at Isaac, though.
I can't lose against him.
And my potions are strong!
What the...
Okay, we got a bad signal here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
There we go!
Get him out of here, Mom's Razor.
Sure, I'll take it.
At this point, I'll take whatever.
We keep going.
Down here.
What do we got here?
Dude, the Jacob's Ladder is so good.
So satisfying.
Especially against so many enemies here.
Okay, so let's go north.
We still have a couple things to do up there.
Oh, we had a room here.
I can't believe I get that mantle every room.
Like, that's just messed up, man.
Triple A battery.
I'm not feeling it.
Pretty good run, huh?
I would say things are going pretty swell.
There's a couple more bosses up here.
Something's gotta happen, though, when I clear all the bosses, no?
Low key!
Underscore.
Like,
is this even a boss?
Spoonbender.
Wait, does that work with my tears?
Guess we'll find out.
See what we got here.
Electricity's gonna be nuts here.
Whoa!
I think it is working.
Bob's Brain.
Uh, familiar?
Okay, it's a familiar one.
Okay, whatever.
I take it.
Don't question it.
Just go.
The cage.
How many bosses have I killed in this run?
Like, it's quite a lot.
Tear Detonator.
What?
Splits all friendly tears on screen into outward launching rings of six tears each.
Say, what now?
It didn't do anything.
Maybe it doesn't work with, uh...
And I'm gonna keep it, just to experiment.
Well, uh, the map is cleared.
Not really sure.
I guess we just go to the chest now.
Okay.
Let's go back.
Maybe I activate this before I shoot?
No.
Okay, I'm not sure.
Uh, not this way.
This way.
We gotta go all the way around.
Go down here.
Actually, just open the map like this.
We can see while we walk.
Fuck!
Wait, was it down here?
I think it was down here.
Yeah, this is it.
Was it here?
I'm not sure it was here.
Uh...
Where was it?
It was also paused on here.
Wait, I'm confused right now.
It was definitely one of these two.
Is this one?
Are
you kidding me?
So this is where I started.
Oh, maybe it was in...
Oh, wait, I think I know where it is.
No, no, no, no.
I...
Wait, what is this room even?
Look at this.
This looks insane.
Oh, uh...
Yeah, okay, keep that.
That's fine.
Doesn't matter at this point.
Ah!
Here we go.
Totally forgot.
Oh, it's a new one.
Man, it went from nice to bad.
That's so sad.
Oh,
oh my god.
Isaac.
That's so sad, man.
Juicy.
We gotta listen to this song, though.
That was a crazy run.
Wow.
What the hell?
No, Jackie.
Jackie, get down.
I'm almost done here, okay?
You can get some food soon.
Wow.
Guys.
That is the perfect way to end this stream.
What a run, man.
That was so good.
Wow.
Oh, shit.
Look, it unlocks?
Okay, okay, wait, wait, you're right, you're right, you're right.
Let me see.
Dark Prince's crown has appeared.
Delirious has appeared in the basement.
Little Delirium has appeared.
Hey, okay.
I mean, guys, that doesn't tell me anything.
It's not like I'm suddenly...
Oh, cool.
Now things...
It's just more items, you know?
It's just three more items out of a million.
It doesn't really matter.
I'm gonna find them at some point, I guess.
No,
I'm gonna go now, guys.
This is a good time to end it.
We're gonna cliffhanger this then with the new items.
Cheers.
I wasn't even gonna stream today.
It was like a last-minute decision.
Hope the cat cooked up something good.
I think so.
It smells amazing.
I think it's my neighbors.
Jagged decided to cook me food, because I always cook her food.
You guys are feeding for Isaac, yeah.
She cooked supper for me.
And if you know what supper is in Isaac, then you can get an idea.
It's the best she can do, okay?
Don't make fun of her.
Yeah, she definitely cooked something in the letterbox, too.
Yeah, health up.
Yeah, I was about...
Isanti, who's more addicted me or you?
I think we're equally addicted right now.
Check what you got in Steam achievements, should I?
Maybe I should.
I mean, it's the same items, guys.
Little delirium, delirious, dark princess crown.
That's pretty much it.
It's the same items.
It doesn't tell me more than what is in the game, you know?
It actually smells like lasagna right now.
Don't worry, we're gonna stream either tomorrow or the day after.
We're gonna have streams, don't worry, we're gonna play more.
I'm also addicted, okay?
I gotta space out the addiction here.
Otherwise, it's too much of the good thing.
Patience is a virtue, exactly.
They're begging.
I hate Mondays and Loveless.
Wait, it's not Monday, though.
It's Saturday.
You know why I played so well today, guys?
It's actually because I got a haircut today.
That's why I played so well.
Because normally, my hair is so long that it's like getting in my eyes and I can't see anything.
But because I have no more hair in my eyes, I can see everything.
I'm not joking.
Like, it always gets in my ears under the headphones.
It's really annoying, but now it's like super nice, you know?
Haircut buff, exactly.
Which music track is your favorite so far?
Oh, man, let me think.
I think it may be...
Oh, I like the one in the area with the water.
And I also like the song that plays in one of those...
Is it a secret room?
Or maybe it's the planetarium?
I'm not sure, but one of those rooms that you almost never see.
And I always love the music so much in there.
I don't want to leave.
Oh, the song...
No, no, my favorite song is the one where the song is playing normally.
And then randomly, when you get into combat, the guitar riff comes in.
You know, and adds on top of it.
What is that one?
Is that Burning Basement?
That's my favorite then.
I love the way it transitions between combat music and non-combat music in Burning Basement.
That's most songs.
I feel like it's more apparent than that one.
I always notice it with that song.
Opinion on Delirium Bullet Hell?
I'm Neo.
My opinion doesn't matter.
I can bend bullets.
There's no spoon.
Did you see me today?
Did you see the way I was weaving and bobbing?
Oh, yeah.
He's beginning to believe.
Oliver, Delirium are fighting.
And they all run to the monitors.
Yeah, Hush was sick.
Has Chat showed you the Isaac copy pasta?
I don't think so.
I didn't even realize there was one.
You played so well against Hush with nothing to block the bullets.
Thank you.
Yeah, I remember one guy in Chat.
Maybe it was last time or the time before them.
Who like vaguely was like insulting me, but not in an evil way.
It was just like...
So do you think you can beat Hush without having all the flies you had?
I feel like that was just like a very indirect way of saying, yeah, you suck, you know?
And you didn't deserve that or something?
Like, what do you mean?
Come on.
Hey, look at me now, eh?
By the way, can I say?
Undefeated against Hush.
Ah, let me see here.
Edmund McMillan, you little fucker.
You made a shit piece with your trash Isaac.
It's fucking bad, this trash game.
I will become back my money.
Hope you will win your next time a cow on a trash farm, you sucker.
What's the context for that one?
I don't know it.
Was it someone on Reddit posting that or was it like an angry email?
Did they send that to Edmund?
This is a review that was tweeted at Edmund, okay.
I mean...
You know this guy died against Hush.
You know he did.
You know this guy suffered through 10,000 rounds of the solar system.
He played too much solar system.
That's what happens when you do that.
Guys, imagine if I had never beaten the solar system, I would still, to this day, be on the solar system.
Every day, all day.
I would have done it.
Aren't you happy I did it?
Okay,
check this out.
Someone wrote, What will you do when it comes to unlocks you cannot reasonably figure out blind?
I feel like that's also a...
Yeah, you're never gonna figure that out, you know.
But I don't know, maybe I will, guys.
I don't know.
I'm okay with not finding everything.
That's fine with me.
You made it sound like, oh, there's not a chance in hell, but...
I mean, it's difficult to get 100% in a game like this, right?
That's not my intention.
I want to play this game until I don't enjoy it anymore, pretty much.
That's really all there is to it.
There's not some kind of goal here other than having fun.
It's all about having fun.
And so far, I'm having a blast.
And I'm gonna keep playing until I don't have a blast anymore.
That's pretty much it.
And it doesn't mean that when I don't have a blast anymore, that the game is bad.
It just means I've probably been playing so much of it, or I'm done with it, or...
You know, that I'm, you know, excited to go play something else.
But we're definitely not at that point yet.
The joke is decomp...
Yeah, what is happening with the...
Are you actually censoring that yourself, or is that Twitch doing that?
I think it's...
No, you're censoring that.
Yeah, yeah, okay.
Well, guys, what should the title for this bot be?
I think I did pretty well with the title in the last one.
Now, we already had a title called Speed before.
Becoming...
Hey, that's a good one!
Becoming back my money!
That's gonna make people think that...
I was raging, right?
Or I was tilting.
I feel like Dementia Cured is just gonna...
You know, it's gonna make people happy until the Dementia comes back, you know?
And then False Promise, it was not really Cured.
I like the one that you just wrote.
What was it?
I will come back my money.
Yes, that's a good title.
Thank you, guys.
That's a great one.
Unless I think of something else.
Hush, little baby!
Okay, I'm out of here.
Jackie needs to eat some food.
I need to eat my neighbors... my own food.
I will see you in the next stream.
Maybe tomorrow, maybe the day after.
And have a wonderful weekend, okay?
I command you to have a great Saturday.
And I'll see you around.
Bye-bye.
Why are you still here?
Get out!
I'm not leaving until you're leaving.
I mean, I can stay here all day.
See ya!